Inventory of the Imre Pozsgay papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Imre Pozsgay papers
1930-2005
(bulk 1953-2005)
96064
Pozsgay, Imre
116 manuscript boxes (58 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Documents relating to political conditions in Hungary during the communist and post-communist periods: speeches and writings, correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, minutes, bulletins, serial issues, printed matter, and audiovisual materials.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1996.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
26 November 1933 Born, Kóny, Hungary
1948-1952 Studied at College of Horticulture, Fertőd, Hungary
1950-1957 Member of the Magyar Dolgozók Pártja, or MDP (the Hungarian Workers' Party, or HWP)
1952-1957 Studied at Lenin Institute, Budapest, Hungary; graduated from the Department of History and Marxism-Leninism
1957-1989 Member of the Magyar Szocialista Munkás Párt, or MSZMP (the Hungarian Socialist Workers' Party, or HSWP)
1957-1968 Leader of several sub-organizations within the HSWP Bács-Kiskun County Committee
1968-1969 Secretary, the HSWP Bács-Kiskun County Committee
1970 Head of Press Section, HSWP Central Committee
1971-1975 Deputy Editor-in-Chief of the HSWP journal Társadalmi Szemle
1975-1976 Hungarian Deputy Minister of Education and Culture
1976-1982 Hungarian Minister of Education and Culture
1982-1988 Secretary General of the Hazafias Népfront, or HNF (the Patriotic Popular Front, or PPF)
1983-1994 Member of the Hungarian Parliament
1988-1990 Hungarian Minister of State
1989-1990 Co-founder and deputy chairman of the Magyar Szocialista Párt, or MSZP (the Hungarian Socialist Party, or HSP)
1991-1996 Co-founder and later chairman of the Nemzeti Demokrata Szövetség, or NDSZ (National Democratic Union, or NDU)
1991-2003 Professor of Political Sciences, Debrecen University, Debrecen, Hungary
1995-2000 Rector of St. László University, Budapest
Scope and Content of Collection
Documents relating to political conditions in Hungary during the communist and post-communist periods: speeches and writings, correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, minutes, bulletins, serial issues, printed matter, and audiovisual materials.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into eight series. Most of the materials are arranged alphabetically and then chronologically.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Hungary--Politics and government--1945-1989; Hungary--Politics and government--1989-; Statesmen--Hungary.
Collection Contents
- Compiled news reports, circa 1985-1990 (Box 1-23)
  Compiled news reports, circa 1985-1990: reports on news articles and other published materials, Hungarian and foreign, concerning mostly Hungarian issues or Imre Pozsgay; some contain compiled newspaper clippings
  Arranged in alphabetical order
  - Cikkek a nemzetközi sajtóból (Folder 1-2)
  - Cikkek a szocialista sajtóból (Folder 2)
  - Elméleti cikkek (Folder 3)
  - Információk a magyar sajtóból (Folder 3)
  - Információk a magyar sajtóból
  - Hírösszefoglaló (Folder 5)
  - Hírösszefoglaló: Reggel (Folder 5-6)
  - Napi tájékoztató (Folder 7-9)
  - Nemzetközi dokumentumok (Folder 10)
  - Öszefoglaló a nagykövetségi sajtószemlékből (Folder 10)
  - Rádiófigyelő (Folder 10-18)
  - A sajtó a jelöltekről (Folder 18)
  - A sajtó a Magyar Szocialista Pártról (Folder 18)
  - A sajtó az MSzMP-ről (Folder 18)
  - A sajtó a pártokról (Folder 19)
  - A sajtó a szocialista pártról (Folder 19)
  - A sajtó a választásról (Folder 19)
  - Sajtófigyelő (Folder 19)
  - Sajtószemle (Folder 19)
  - Szemelvények az emigrációs sajtóból (Folder 19-20)
  - Szemle a nyugati rádiók magyar nyelvű adásaiból (Folder 20-21)
  - Fragments of news reports (Folder 21)
  - Reports on and translations of individual articles and publications, 1976-1991 and undated (Folder 22-23)
- Periodicals, circa 1975-1995 (Box 23-44)
  Hungarian official and samizdat periodicals, foreign periodicals; articles mostly on Hungarian issues or on Imre Pozsgay
  - 24 Óra: Komárom-Esztergom megyei napilap (Folder 23)
  - 168 Óra (Folder 23-24)
  - 2000: Irodalmi és Társadalmi Havi Lap (Folder 24)
  - Amerikai Magyar Népszava (Folder 24)
  - Amerikai Magyar Szó (Folder 24)
  - Aréna (Folder 24)
  - Ausztria: A Világgazdaság melléklete (Folder 24)
  - Bács Kapocs (Folder 24)
  - Barométer (Folder 24)
  - Bécsi Napló (Folder 24)
  - Békes Megyei Népújság (Folder 24)
  - Beszélő (Folder 24)
  - Budapest (Folder 25)
  - Budapester Rundschau (Folder 25)
  - Bulgarian periodicals (Folder 25)
  - Búvár (Folder 25)
  - A Céh (Folder 25)
  - CHRR Bulletin (Folder 25)
  - Confessio (Folder 25)
  - Cor Unum (Folder 25)
  - Csongrád Megyei Hírlap (Folder 25)
  - Daily News - Neueste Nachrichten, MTI (Folder 25)
  - Dátum (Folder 25)
  - Dél-Kelet (Folder 25)
  - Déli Hírlap (Folder 25)
  - Délmagyarország (Folder 25)
  - Délvilág (Folder 25)
  - Demokrata (Folder 25)
  - Diakonia (Folder 25)
  - Diana: a magyar úrinők magazinja (Folder 25)
  - Dolgozók Lapja: Az MSzMP Komárom Megyei Bizottsága és a Megyei Tanács lapja (Folder 25)
  - Dolgozók Lapja, Tatabánya (Folder 25)
  - A Döntő (Folder 25)
  - Duna: svájci magyar tudosító (Folder 25)
  - A Duna Kör Hírei (Folder 25)
  - Dunántúli Napló (Folder 25)
  - Dunaújvárosi Hírlap (Folder 25)
  - Ébredő Magyarság (Folder 25)
  - Ef-Lapok (Folder 25)
  - Egyetemi Élet: A debreceni egyetemek és főiskolák lapja (Folder 25)
  - Egyetemi Lapok: Az Eötvös Loránd Tudományegyetem lapja (Folder 25)
  - Egyetemünk: a veszprémi vegyipari lapja (Folder 25)
  - EK Tájékoztató (Folder 25)
  - Elefánt Kurír (Folder 25)
  - Élet és Irodalom (Folder 26)
  - Előre (Folder 26)
  - English-language periodicals: American, Australian, British and Japanese (Folder 26)
  - Erdélyi Magyarság (Folder 26)
  - És (Folder 26)
  - Esti Hírlap (Folder 26)
  - Észak-Magyarország (Folder 26)
  - Evangélikus Élet (Folder 26)
  - Évforduló (Folder 26)
  - Fakta (Folder 26)
  - Fanyar Hírlap (Folder 26)
  - Fehérvári Hét (Folder 26)
  - Fejér Megyei Hírlap (Folder 26)
  - Figyelő (Folder 27)
  - Film-Színház-Muzsika (Folder 27)
  - Finnish periodicals (Folder 27)
  - French periodicals (Folder 27)
  - German-language periodicals: Austrian, German and Swiss (Folder 27)
  - Gödöllői Hívogató (Folder 27)
  - Gödöllői Mindenes (Folder 27)
  - Gyermekünk (Folder 27)
  - Győri Futár (Folder 27)
  - Hajdú-Bihari Napló (Folder 27)
  - Halasi Tükör (Folder 27)
  - Hát... Tér (Folder 27)
  - A Helyzet (Folder 27)
  - Hétfői Hírek: politikai hetilap (Folder 27)
  - Heti Kis Újság (Folder 27)
  - Heti Magyarország (Folder 28)
  - Heti Világgazdaság (Folder 28)
  - Hétpróba (Folder 28)
  - Heves Megyei Népújság (Folder 28)
  - Hírlevél: Magyar Zsidó Kulturális Egyesület (Folder 28)
  - Hírmondó (Folder 28)
  - Hírmondó: Az MSzP Százhalombattai szervezetének lapja (Folder 28)
  - História (Folder 28)
  - Hitel (Folder 28-29)
  - Hócipő (Folder 29)
  - Horizont: a nemzetközi kapsolatok magazinja (Folder 29)
  - The Hungarian Observer (Folder 29)
  - Az Ifju Proletár, 1919/1968 (Folder 29)
    a 50th anniversary edition of the newspaper's first issue
  - Ifjúkommunista (Folder 29)
  - Igaz Szó (Folder 29)
  - Indian periodicals (Folder 29)
  - Intézményi Hírlevél (Folder 29)
  - Invest in Hungary (Folder 29)
  - Irodalmi Újság (Folder 29)
  - Israeli periodicals (Folder 29)
  - Italian periodicals (Folder 30)
  - Itt-Ott (Folder 30)
  - Jel-Kép (Folder 30)
  - A Jövő Mérnöke: a Budapesti Műszaki Egyetem lapja (Folder 30)
  - A Jövő Üzemmérnöke (Folder 30)
  - Június 16: Az Igazság emlékszáma, 1989 (Folder 30)
  - Juventud Rebelde (Folder 30)
  - Kacsa Magazin (Folder 30)
  - Kapu (Folder 30)
  - Karima (Folder 30)
  - Kárpát-Medencei Kapcsolatok (Folder 30)
  - Katolikus Szó (Folder 30)
  - Kecskeméti Lapok (Folder 30)
  - Kék Balatoni Futár (Folder 30)
  - Kék Bolygó (Folder 30)
  - Kelet-Magyarország (Folder 30)
  - Képes 7 (Folder 30)
  - Képes Sport (Folder 30)
  - Képes Újság (Folder 30)
  - Kert (Folder 30)
  - Kiegyezés (Folder 30)
  - Kis Újság (Folder 30)
  - Kisalföld (Folder 30)
  - Kispest (Folder 31)
  - Komárom-Esztergom Dolgozók Lapja (Folder 31)
  - Könyvvilág (Folder 31)
  - Körkép (Folder 31)
  - Közgáz Évkönyv (Folder 31)
  - Közgazdász (Folder 31)
  - Köznevelés (Folder 31)
  - Közös Úton (Folder 31)
  - Kritika (Folder 31)
  - Kulcsszavak (Folder 31)
  - Külgazdaság (Folder 31)
  - Külpolitika (Folder 31)
  - Kurír (Folder 31)
  - Kutya (Folder 31)
  - Lakáskultúra (Folder 31)
  - Leninvárosi Krónika (Folder 31)
  - Ludas (Folder 31)
  - Ludas Matyi (Folder 31)
  - Magyar Felsőoktatás (Folder 31)
  - Magyar Figyelő (Folder 31)
  - Magyar Fórum (Folder 31)
  - Magyar Híradó, Wien (Folder 31)
  - Magyar Hírek (Folder 31)
  - Magyar Hírlap (Folder 32-33)
  - Magyar Honvéd (Folder 33)
  - Magyar Ifjuság (Folder 33)
  - A Magyar Kodály Társaság Hírei (Folder 33)
  - Magyar Konyha (Folder 33)
  - Magyar Közlöny (Folder 33)
  - Magyar Kurir: félhivatalos egyházi lap (Folder 33)
  - Magyar Mezőgazdaság (Folder 33)
  - Magyar Napló (Folder 33)
  - Magyar Narancs (Folder 33)
  - Magyar Nemzet (Folder 33-35)
  - Magyar Nők (Folder 35)
  - Magyar Rendőr (Folder 35)
  - Magyar Szó (Folder 35)
  - Magyar Zsidó (Folder 35)
  - Magyarország (Folder 35)
  - Mai Nap (Folder 35)
  - Mai Reggel (Folder 35)
  - Márczius Tizenötödike (Folder 35)
  - Medicor Hangja (Folder 35)
  - Menóra (Folder 35)
  - Mezőgazdasági Mérnök (Folder 35)
  - Miskolci Fórum (Folder 35)
  - Montreáli Magyarság (Folder 35)
  - Mozgó Világ (Folder 35)
  - MTV Demokrata Szem-pont (Folder 35)
  - Műhely (Folder 35)
  - Művészet (Folder 36)
  - El Nacional (Folder 36)
  - Nagyatád (Folder 36)
  - Nap (Folder 36)
  - Napi: gazdaság, üzlet, világ, politika (Folder 36)
  - Napjaink (Folder 36)
  - Napló (Folder 36)
  - Napóra (Folder 36)
  - Narodne novine: list demokratskog saveza južnih Slavena u Mađarskoj (Folder 36)
  - Népfront (Folder 36)
  - Népi Ellenőrzés (Folder 36)
  - Népművelés (Folder 36)
  - Népsport (Folder 36)
  - Népszabadság (Folder 36-38)
  - Népszava (Folder 39)
  - Néptanácsadó (Folder 39)
  - Népújság (Folder 39)
  - Neueste Nachrichten (Folder 39)
  - News from Hungary (Folder 39)
  - Nógrád (Folder 39)
  - Nők Lapja (Folder 39)
  - Nyugati Magyarság (Folder 39)
  - Őrség (Folder 39)
  - Ország Világ (Folder 39)
  - Országházi Hírek (Folder 39)
  - Ösztöndíjas (Folder 39)
  - Ötlet (Folder 40)
  - Paksi Mozaik (Folder 40)
  - Pedagógusok Lapja (Folder 40)
  - Pest Megyei Hírlap (Folder 40)
  - Pesti Hírlap (Folder 40)
  - Petőfi Népe (Folder 40)
  - Phralipe (Folder 40)
  - Polish periodicals (Folder 40)
  - Psycho (Folder 41)
  - Rádió- és Televízióújság (Folder 41)
  - Rajta (Folder 41)
  - Reform (Folder 41)
  - Reformátusok Lapja (Folder 41)
  - Reformkörök (Folder 41)
  - Ring (Folder 41)
  - Riport (Folder 42)
  - Romanian periodicals (Folder 42)
  - Russian-language periodicals: Soviet and Hungarian (Folder 42)
  - Sajtótisztesség (Folder 42)
  - Sárospatak (Folder 42)
  - Siklós (Folder 42)
  - Somogy (Folder 42)
  - Somogyi Néplap (Folder 42)
  - Somogyország (Folder 42)
  - Soproni Egyetem (Folder 42)
  - Sport Plusz (Folder 42)
  - Sport Revü (Folder 42)
  - Szabad Európa (Folder 42)
  - Szabad Föld (Folder 42)
  - Szabadelvű UNIO (Folder 42)
  - Szabadság (Folder 42)
  - Szakkollégiumi Értesítő (Folder 42)
  - Számadás (Folder 42)
  - Széchényi Füzetek (Folder 42)
  - Szegedi Egyetem (Folder 42)
  - Szélrózsa (Folder 42)
  - Szocialista Művészetért (Folder 42)
  - Szocialista Szavazó Lap (Folder 42)
  - Szombat (Folder 42)
  - Szövetkezeti Hírmagazin (Folder 42)
  - T-Boy (Folder 42)
  - Tallózó (Folder 42)
  - Táncsics Krónika (Folder 42)
  - Telehír (Folder 42)
  - Tér-Kép (Folder 42)
  - Transnational Data Report (Folder 42)
  - Tubus: A tiszadobiak lapja (Folder 42)
  - Új Demokrata (Folder 43)
  - Új Dunántúli Napló (Folder 43)
  - Új Élet: a magyar izraeliták lapja (Folder 43)
  - Új Ember (Folder 43)
  - Új Forrás (Folder 43)
  - Új Fórum (Folder 43)
  - Új Idő (Folder 43)
  - Új Írás (Folder 43)
  - Új Kelet (Folder 43)
  - Új Könyvek (Folder 43)
  - Új Köröstáj (Folder 43)
  - Új Ludas (Folder 43)
  - Új Magyarország (Folder 43)
  - Új Nemzedékért (Folder 43)
  - Új Szabad Száj (Folder 43)
  - Új Tükör (Folder 43)
  - Váci Hírlap (Folder 43)
  - Városépítés (Folder 43)
  - Vas Népe (Folder 43)
  - Vasárnapi Hírek (Folder 43)
  - Veszprém Megyei Napló (Folder 44)
  - Veszprém Megyei Új Hírek (Folder 44)
  - Vigyázó (Folder 44)
  - Világ: politikai hetilap (Folder 44)
  - Zalai Hírlap (Folder 44)
  - Unidentified periodicals, 1988-1991 and undated (Folder 44)
- Photocopies of archival materials, 1956-1989 (Box 44-56)
  documents on interior and foreign affairs from Hungarian state institutions; the majority are Magyar Szocialista Munkás Párt Központi Bizottsága (MSZMP KB) and Magyar Szocialista Munkás Párt Politikai Bizottsága (MSZMP PB) documents; most of the documents are minutes of meetings, reports and correspondence
  Arranged in alphabetical and subsequently chronological order
  - Agitációs és Propaganda Bizottság, 1962-1988 (Folder 44)
  - Brezhnev, Leonid I., 1964-1981 (Folder 45)
    correspondence with János Kádár; MSZMP KB and MSZMP PB reports and minutes of meetings
  - Déry, Tibor, 1963-1964 (Folder 45)
    correspondence, reports
  - Illyés, Gyula, 1964 (Folder 45)
    Agitációs és Propaganda Bizottság reports
  - Irodalmunk helyzete és problémai, circa 1964 (Folder 45)
    a research paper on literature by Miklós Szabolcsi (?)
  - Keleti, Márton, 1965 and undated (Folder 45)
    correspondence, János Kádár, György Aczél, István Szirmai
  - Kodály, Zoltán, 1962-1964 (Folder 45)
    correspondence, János Kádár, György Aczél; MSZMP KB and MSZMP PB reports and minutes
  - MSZMP, 1964 (Folder 45)
    MSZMP országos ideológiai konferencia, 24-25 September 1964, minutes
  - MSZMP Elnöksége, 1989 (Folder 45)
  - MSZMP Intéző Bizottsága, 1956-1957 (Folder 45-46)
    - MSZMP Intéző Bizottsága, 1956 (Folder 45)
    - MSZMP Intéző Bizottsága, 1957 (Folder 46)
  - MSZMP KB, 1956-1989 (Folder 46-51)
    - MSZMP KB, 1956-1957 (Folder 46)
    - MSZMP KB, 1957-1958 (Folder 47)
    - MSZMP KB, 1959-1960 (Folder 48)
    - MSZMP KB, 1960-1965 (Folder 49)
    - MSZMP KB, 1966-1975 (Folder 50)
    - MSZMP KB, 1981-1989 (Folder 51)
  - MSZMP PB, 1957-1989 (Folder 51-56)
    - MSZMP PB, 1957 (Folder 51)
    - MSZMP PB, 1957-1958 (Folder 52)
    - MSZMP PB, 1958-1960 (Folder 53)
    - MSZMP PB, 1960-1969 (Folder 54)
    - MSZMP PB, 1971-1989 (Folder 55)
    - MSZMP PB, 1989 (Folder 56)
  - MSZMP Titkársága, 1973 (Folder 56)
    reports from MSZMP KB Tudományos, Közoktatási és Kulturális Osztály, minutes of meetings
  - Művelődésügyi Minisztérium, 1964 (Folder 56)
  - Péter, György, 1969-1973 (Folder 56)
    correspondence, Vera Horvát, János Kádár, and Emmi Pikler; MSZMP PB and MSZMP KB reports and minutes
  - The Prague Spring, 1968-1969 and undated (Folder 56)
    reports on meetings between János Kádár and Alexander Dubček, other MSZMP PB and MSZMP KB reports, minutes, and correspondence
  - Veres, Péter, 1958 (Folder 56)
    correspondence, János Kádár
- Brief correspondence and writings, 1979-1995 and undated (Box 57)
  letters and invitations, some with attached periodicals or newspaper clippings; short reports, articles and papers
  - Antall, József, 1989, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Bálint, Éva, 1984 (Folder 57)
  - Balogh, Dénes, 1990 (Folder 57)
  - Bánk, József, 1986 (Folder 57)
  - Bánó, István, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Baranyai, Antal, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Báron, Ferenc, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Bauer, Tamás, undated (Folder 57)
  - Beregszászi Illyés Gyula Magyar Nemzeti Színház Alapítvány, 1995 (Folder 57)
  - Bernáth, Zoltán, circa 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Bloom, Benjamin S., 1986 (Folder 57)
  - Bolgár Népköztársaság Nagykövetsége, 1985 (Folder 57)
  - Bossányi, Katalin, 1990 (Folder 57)
  - Brády, Zoltán, 1987 (Folder 57)
  - Brezer, Karl, 1992 (Folder 57)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation, David Morton, 1986 (Folder 57)
  - British Embassy, Budapest, 1995 (Folder 57)
  - Bücher aus Ungarn, 1988 (Folder 57)
  - Budapest Reklám, 1995 (Folder 57)
  - Budapesti Magánlakásépitési Információs és Szolgálató Iroda, Tiborné Gombás, 1984 (Folder 57)
  - Bush, George, undated (Folder 57)
    a photocopy of a signed photograph of Imre Pozsgay with George Bush
  - C. Itoh and Co., 1984 (Folder 57)
  - Casaroli, Augustino, 1990 (Folder 57)
    a letter to Endre Gyulay, in Latin and translated into Hungarian
  - Császtvay, István and József Sárándi, 1982 (Folder 57)
  - A Csehszlovákiai Magyar Kissebség Jogvédő Bizottsága, 1987 (Folder 57)
  - Deák, László, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Debreceni Kör, 1983 (Folder 57)
  - Eff, Lajos, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Fehér, Vilmosné, 1990 (Folder 57)
  - Ferenczy, Csaba, undated (Folder 57)
  - Figyelő, György Varga, 1986 (Folder 57)
  - Fispán, Géza, 1987 (Folder 57)
  - Földváry, Attila, undated (Folder 57)
  - Freymond, Jacques, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Gosztonyi, Péter, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Gubcsi, Lajos, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Gyenesei, István, 1990 (Folder 57)
  - Hajdu, József, 1984 (Folder 57)
  - Havel, Václav, 1990 (Folder 57)
  - Házi, Vencel, undated (Folder 57)
  - Henkey, Gyula, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Heti Világgazdaság, 1988, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Hlavács, József, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Hoós, János, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Horgas, Béla, 1988 (Folder 57)
  - Horn, Emil, undated (Folder 57)
    an article on Raoul Wallenberg
  - L'Institut Hongrois de Paris, circa 1982 (Folder 57)
  - Jenei, Tibor, circa 1983 (Folder 57)
  - Jókai, Anna, undated (Folder 57)
  - Juhász, Ferenc, 1979,1982 (Folder 57)
  - Kaderják, Péter, 1987 and undated (Folder 57)
  - Káldy, Zoltán, 1984 (Folder 57)
  - Kállay, Miklós, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Kanadai Magyarok Szövetsége, András Timár, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Kardos, György, 1980 (Folder 57)
    a letter to Vladimir Farkas
  - Kárpáti, István, undated (Folder 57)
  - Katona, Zsuzsanna, 1994 (Folder 57)
  - Kenessey, Csaba, 1995 (Folder 57)
  - Kéri, László, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Kivistö, Kalevi, undated (Folder 57)
  - Ködmögötti, Pál, undated (Folder 57)
  - Komlós, Attila, undated (Folder 57)
  - Kono, Yohei, 1987 (Folder 57)
  - Kopré, József, undated (Folder 57)
  - Kossuth Lajos Tudományegyetem, László Nagy, 1993 (Folder 57)
  - Kovács, Győző, undated (Folder 57)
  - Kovács, Imre P., undated (Folder 57)
  - Kovár, Gyula, 1995 (Folder 57)
  - Közgazdász, Gabriella Molnár, 1984 (Folder 57)
  - Krasznai, Zoltán, undated (Folder 57)
  - Kurier, György Berényi, 1990 (Folder 57)
  - Laczó, József, 1986 (Folder 57)
  - László, Andor, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Lékai, László, 1980-1985 (Folder 57)
  - Lengyel, László, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Magyar Alkotók és Gondolkodók, 1995 and undated (Folder 57)
  - Magyar Ellenállási Szövetség, 1992 (Folder 57)
  - Magyar Építőművészek Szövetsége, Antal Lázár, 1983 (Folder 57)
  - "Magyar Jövőért" Alapítvány, 1992 (Folder 57)
  - Magyar Katolikus Püspöki Kar, 1986 (Folder 57)
  - Magyar Szellemi Védegylet and András Sándor, 1993 (Folder 57)
  - Magyar Természetgyógyászok Kamarája, 1993 (Folder 57)
  - Magyar Vadászok Országos Szövetsége, 1985 (Folder 57)
  - Magyarországi Cigányok Kulturális Szövetsége, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Makó, Csaba, undated (Folder 57)
  - Máté, András, undated (Folder 57)
  - Melia, Thomas O., 1990 (Folder 57)
  - Mezei, András, undated (Folder 57)
  - Modránszky, László, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Monics, Jurij, 1988 (Folder 57)
  - Mónus, Imre, 1990 (Folder 57)
  - Mózsi, Ferenc, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Nagy, Jenő, 1990 (Folder 57)
    a letter to Illetékes Rehabilitációs Hivatal
  - Nagy, Pongrác, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - National Bank of Hungary, New York, Imre Hollai, 1988 (Folder 57)
  - Nemzeti Pedagógus Műhely, 1995 (Folder 57)
  - Népi Iparművészeti Tanács, László Nagy, 1983 (Folder 57)
  - The New Hungarian Quarterly, 1987 (Folder 57)
  - Nyers, Rezső, undated (Folder 57)
  - Nyugdíjbiztosítás Önkormányzat, Sándor Nagy, 1994 (Folder 57)
  - Nyulászi, Mihály, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Oláh, Imre, undated (Folder 57)
  - Országos Idegenforgalmi Tanács, 1987 (Folder 57)
    minutes of a meeting
  - Országos Környezet- és Természetvédelmi Hivatal, 1985 (Folder 57)
  - Országos Szövetkezeti Tanács, 1995 (Folder 57)
  - Az Osztrák Evangélikus Egyház, undated (Folder 57)
  - Paskai, László, 1987 (Folder 57)
  - Pécs-Somogyi Általános Iskola, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Perecz, László, 1985 (Folder 57)
  - Pesti Hírlap, Ferenc Kőszegi, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Petőfi Népe, 1995 (Folder 57)
  - Práger, László, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Püski, Sándor, 1988 (Folder 57)
  - Rábaközi, András, undated (Folder 57)
  - Rédey, Pál, 1985 (Folder 57)
  - Révffy, László, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Rományi, Béla, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Sánta, Áron, undated (Folder 57)
  - Sára, Sándor, undated (Folder 57)
  - Schőner, Alfréd, 1986 (Folder 57)
  - Soós, Pál, 1987 (Folder 57)
  - Sváby, Lajos, 1993 (Folder 57)
  - Szabó, (?)-né, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Szabolcs-Szátmár Megyei Tanács, 1988 (Folder 57)
  - Szénbányász Munkatanácsok Egyeztető Fóruma, 1990 (Folder 57)
  - Szendi, József, 1988 (Folder 57)
  - Szovjet Irodalom, István Király, 1982 (Folder 57)
  - Szovjet Nagykövetség, Budapest, 1983, 1985 and undated (Folder 57)
  - Takács, Imre, undated (Folder 57)
  - Takács, István, 1991 (Folder 57)
  - Táncsics Mihály Kistáji Népfőiskola, 1992 (Folder 57)
  - Társadalmi Védnökség, 1988 (Folder 57)
  - Textilipari Dolgozók Szakszervezete, 1990 (Folder 57)
  - Thermal Hotel Helia, Gábor Galla, 1990 (Folder 57)
  - Thoma, László, undated (Folder 57)
  - Tornyai János Múzeum and Lóránd Bereczky, 1985 (Folder 57)
  - Tóth, Dezső, 1979 (Folder 57)
  - Tóth, György, undated (Folder 57)
  - Tóth, László, 1986 (Folder 57)
  - Townsend, Douglas, 1992 (Folder 57)
  - Tudományos Ismeretterjeztő Társulat, 1985 (Folder 57)
  - Új kelet, Ottó Rappaport, 1983 (Folder 57)
  - Új tükör, Sándor Fekete, 1981, 1985 (Folder 57)
  - United States Embassy, 1983 (Folder 57)
  - Varga, Lajos Károly, undated (Folder 57)
  - Varga, Mihály, 1987 (Folder 57)
  - Vass, Csaba, 1990 (Folder 57)
  - Vogel, Bernhard, undated (Folder 57)
  - Vogel, Hans-Jochen, 1989 (Folder 57)
  - Voszka, Éva, undated (Folder 57)
  - Wiener, György, undated (Folder 57)
  - Wintermantel, István, undated (Folder 57)
  - World Intellectual Property Organization, Arpad Bogsch, 1981 (Folder 57)
  - Unidentified correspondence, fragmentary correspondence, 1979-1995 and undated (Folder 57)
  - Unidentified correspondence, 1987-1988 and undated (Folder 57)
    issues of Füzet and Karima attached
- Alphabetical file, 1953-1995 and undated (Box 58-88)
  correspondence, reports, published and unpublished writings, promotional materials, and other documents; from individuals, organizations, and organized events
  - Az 1956-os Igazság Baráti Társaság, 1993 (Folder 58)
    a report
  - Ábel, István, 1988 and undated (Folder 58)
    reports, a bibliography of his writings